Bauchwitz, Kurt (Roy C. Bates); Papers ger011
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Manuscripts and Typescripts, 1928-1977; 3; 209 file folders
  - Poetry, Epigrammatic Verse, Aphorisms, 1928-1977; 3.1; 115 file folders
    - "Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams selected by the author from his earlier writings. In German, pre-1940; 3.1.22 (Box 10 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 8-13)
      - "Versepigramme I & II" (Box 10 (3.1.22-"Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams ), Folder 9)
        Pc. of originals. 2 copies, 91p. ea. Table of contents. Pc. 2c., 5p. ea. Notes regarding textual discrepancies. Pc. 2c. 2p.ea.
      - "Versepigramme I" (Box 10 (3.1.22-"Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams ), Folder 10)
        Retyped version of original, with verse-epigrams typed one to a page. Typescript and pc. 158p. Table of contents. Pc. 3p. List of corrections from original. Typescript 2p.
      - "Versepigramme II" (Box 10 (3.1.22-"Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams ), Folder 11)
        Retyped version of original, with verse-epigrams typed one to a page. Typescript and pc. 101p. Table of contents. Typescript 2p.
      - "Versepigramme I & II" (Box 10 (3.1.22-"Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams ), Folder 12)
        Photocopies of retyped version. Incomplete, due to removal of pages for a later anthology ("Der Zitronenbaum"). Pc. 187p. Table of contents. 5p. Notes. Pc. 2p.
      - "Versepigramme von Kurt Bauchwitz" (Box 10 (3.1.22-"Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams ), Folder 13)
        Original Typescript incorporating corrections from the first typescript version. Poems are typed one to a page, although the original page numbering is retained. Pages are numbered Ep. 1 - Ep. 91. Typescript 248p. Title page includes the note "Copyright: Barbara Bates", indicating that this version was probably typed after Bates' death, circa 1977. Alphabetical listing of poems with page numbers. Typescript 7p.
    - "Silben: Haiku und tanka", Undated; 3.1.23 (Box 10 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 14-18)
      175 haiku and tanka, of which the first 117 were written in Japan (1940), the remainder in Milton, Massachusetts (1966).
      - "Silben II", 1966 March 15-16 (Box 10 (3.1.23-"Silben: Haiku und tanka"), Folder 14)
        Original Typescript and Ms. with h. corr. and notes by the author dated March 15/16, 1966 Typescript 8p. Autograph 3p.
      - "Silben: Haiku und tanka", 36p (Box 10 (3.1.23-"Silben: Haiku und tanka"), Folder 15)
        Copy of the entire 175 haiku and tanka. Cc. with h. corr. by the author.
      - "Silben: Haiku und tanka" (Box 10 (3.1.23-"Silben: Haiku und tanka"), Folder 16)
        Photocopies of corrected carbon typescript. 2c., 36p. ea.
      - "Silben: Haiku und Tanka", ca. 1977; 35p (Box 10 (3.1.23-"Silben: Haiku und tanka"), Folder 17)
      - "Silben: Haiku und Tanka", 35p (Box 10 (3.1.23-"Silben: Haiku und tanka"), Folder 18)
        Pc. of 1977 version.
    - "Roy's Amuse", Undated; 9p (Box 10 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 19)
      Short sayings, aphorisms, in English. Typescript with minor corr.
    - "Roy's Amuse", Undated (Box 10 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 20)
      Copy of original 9p. Typescript, with additional pages added. Later section dated 2/28/62. Cc. 16p.
    - "Ego and Echo". Epigrams in English, 1965-1972; 3.1.26 (Box 11 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1-4)
      - "Ego and Echo" (Box 11 (3.1.26-"Ego and Echo". Epigrams in English), Folder 1)
        Notebooks containing epigrams in English, later retyped to form the basis of "Ego and Echo". 4 stenographer notebooks ca. 75 leaves ea.; 1 small zippered loose leaf notebook, ca. 100 leaves.
      - "Ego and Echo" (Box 11 (3.1.26-"Ego and Echo". Epigrams in English), Folder 2)
        Combination of original typescript, manuscript (5p.) and carbons, with numerous h. corr. Epigrams are numbered 1-406 and dated 1/1/66 - 11/25/1972. 139p. Second copy of pp. 129-139. Cc. 12p.
      - "Ego and Echo", 139p (Box 11 (3.1.26-"Ego and Echo". Epigrams in English), Folder 3)
        Pc. of 1965-1972 collection of epigrams.
      - "Ego and Echo", 1960s; ca. 50p (Box 11 (3.1.26-"Ego and Echo". Epigrams in English), Folder 4)
        Notes concerning epigrams.
    - "Ego und Echo: Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'". Anthology of poetry and epigrammatic verse, selected and edited by Harry Zohn, Brandeis University, ca. 1972; 3.1.27 (Box 11 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 5-8)
      - "Ego und Echo: Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'", 88p (Box 11 (3.1.27-"Ego und Echo: Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'". Anthology ), Folder 5)
        First version consists of photocopies of poems from Der Lebendige, original typescripts and carbons.
      - "Ego und Echo: Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'". Herausgegeben von Harry Zohn, ca. 1972; 118p (Box 11 (3.1.27-"Ego und Echo: Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'". Anthology ), Folder 6)
        Photocopy of retyped version.
      - Typescripts of poems returned to Barbara Bates by Harry Zohn, 3/7/76; 21p (Box 11 (3.1.27-"Ego und Echo: Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'". Anthology ), Folder 7)
        Mostly carbons, many with notes attached (in handwriting of Barbara Bates).
      - Boston Globe Book Festival readings, October 8, 1972; 22p (Box 11 (3.1.27-"Ego und Echo: Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'". Anthology ), Folder 8)
        Boston Globe Book Festival readings. Typescripts and carbons of verse epigrams and poems in English, read by Roy Bates at the Boston Globe Book Festival.
        Copy of newspaper cl. (Milton Record-Transcript, October 5, 1972, p. 17) announcing the Globe Book Festival.
    - "Der Zitronenbaum", ca. 1977; 3.1.28 (Box 11 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 9-12)
      Undated version of Ms. prepared by Mireille v. Ehrenfels, Rolf von Ehrenfels, Almut Baader and Ilse Reichenbach. Also referred to as "Berkau manuscript".
      - "Der Zitronenbaum", 144p (Box 11 (3.1.28-"Der Zitronenbaum"), Folder 9)
      - "Der Zitronenbaum", 37p (Box 11 (3.1.28-"Der Zitronenbaum"), Folder 10)
        Poems originally selected as part of the edition but later eliminated from Ehrenfels/Berkau version. Typescript cc.
      - "Der Zitronenbaum", 13p (Box 11 (3.1.28-"Der Zitronenbaum"), Folder 11)
        Various working versions of the table of contents. Typescript and cc. with notes and corr.
      - "Der Zitronenbaum" (Box 11 (3.1.28-"Der Zitronenbaum"), Folder 12)
        Later version, many poems retyped. Title page contains the comment "Copyright: Barbara Bates". Typescript 194p. Extra copies of table of contents pages. Typescript with h. corr. 2c., 2p. ea.
    - Alphabetical listing of poems by title, including dates written. Prepared as an additional finding aid to the collection, 2003 February; 42p (Box 11 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 13)
    - Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram, Undated; 3.1.30 (Box 11 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 14-24)
      Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams, arranged alphabetically by title. Includes variant versions. Mostly pc., some carbon copies.
      - A - 80 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 14)
      - B - 58 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 15)
      - C - 6 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 16)
      - D - 58 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 17)
      - E - 61 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 18)
      - F - 31 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 19)
      - G - 45 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 20)
      - H - 44 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 21)
      - I - 23 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 22)
      - J - 8 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 23)
      - K - 32 poems, epigrams (Box 11 (3.1.30-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigram), Folder 24)
    - Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams, Undated; 3.1.31 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1-14)
      - L - 23 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 1)
      - M - 41 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 2)
      - N - 27 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 3)
      - O - 21 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 4)
      - P - 55 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 5)
      - Q - 3 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 6)
      - R - 34 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 7)
      - S - 76 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 8)
      - T - 33 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 9)
      - U - 41 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 10)
      - V - 40 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 11)
      - W - 35 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 12)
      - X, Y - 1 poem (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 13)
      - Z - 24 poems, epigrams (Box 12 (3.1.31-Duplicate copies of individual poems and epigrams), Folder 14)
    - Tables of contents, title pages., Undated (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 15)
      Duplicate copies. Pc. and cc. 55p.
  - Prose Writings, 1940-1974; 3.2; 94 file folders
    The prose writings are arranged chronologically and consist of short prose pieces in German and in English, and the later prose writings written almost entirely in English. These include Bates' loosely autobiographical observations, the first series collectively entitled "Pebbles" and the later series entitled "Question Marks". Also included in this section are the outlines of Bates' "Biotechnics" with notes for a "Biosophic Seminar", accompanied by numerous note slips divided into the various categories of biosophy, as defined by Bates.
    - Short prose in German, 1940s (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 16)
      Includes typescripts of:
      "The Ballistic Line". Dated Januar 1942, N.Y. Typescript with h. corr. 15p.
      "Der Vergessliche". Dated 31. Januar 1942, N.Y. Typescript with h. corr. 8p.
      "Brautwerbund". Undated. Typescript with h. corr. 8p.
      "Die Glocken". Undated. Typescript with h. corr. 4p.
      "Tropical Fishes. An District Attorney Leonard F. Glenn Re Mordaffaere Clinton". Undated. Typescript with h. corr. 8p.
    - Psychological topics. Notes and research materials, 1938; 1941; Undated (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 17)
      Autograph and Typescript 14p. 1 cl.
    - "Themen", 1942 January-1942 February (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 18)
      Typewritten notes on various topics, in German. Typescript 9p.
    - "How American Librarians Can Help Win the Peace". Essay written by Bates to accompany his application for admittance to Columbia University, 1942 April 13; 4p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 19)
    - "Reno. A Subject of Field Investigation". Written for Fundamentals of Library Service course, Columbia University, Summer Session 1942 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 20)
      Finished text. 3c. Typescript and cc. 20p. ea. Earlier version. Typescript with numerous h. corr. 16p.
    - "History of Books and Printing: In Quest of the First Colonial American Printer". Written for Columbia University Summer Session, 1941 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 21)
      Typescript and cc. 5c. 19p. ea.
    - "The Unwritten History of Quotation Marks or The Ethical Symbol in Print And Its Unwritten History". Handwritten title: "The Ethics of Quotation Marks", 1942 July 07; 2p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 22)
    - "What's Wrong with the United States? What's Wrong with America?" Research materials on the United States and Japan, 1942 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 23)
      Autograph and Typescript ca. 30p. Accompanied by a research request in the form of a letter from the New York Public Library (Jennie M. Flexner, Readers' Adviser), dated May 1, 1942.
    - "Reference Material on Japan". Written for Columbia University course, Library Service 262, 1943 April; 34p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 24)
    - "Deutschlands groesste Stunde", 1943 December 06 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 25)
      Typescript with numerous corr. 7p. Later version. Typescript cc. with some h. corr. 6p.
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1943-1944; Undated (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 26)
      Handwritten notes on a variety of topics, including notes on books. Autograph ca. 80p.
    - Miscellaneous notes, Undated; ca. 120p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 27)
    - Short prose, prose fragments, aphorisms, in English, ca. 1945-1947; Undated (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 28)
      Autograph 18p. Typescript and cc. ca. 115p.
    - "Cloud Cuckoo Town Library", ca. 1945; 5p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 29)
      2 earlier versions. Typescript with h. corr. 5p., 6p.
    - "The Social Angle in Heart Research", 1946-1947 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 30)
      Typescript 3p. Research materials, notes. Autograph 2p. Typescript 21p. Also 3 cl.
    - Encyclopedia, dictionary ideas, ca. 1946-1947 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 31)
      Descriptions for proposed encyclopedias, ideas, notes. Typescript 56p.
    - "Second Wind". Notes and ideas for a proposed magazine, 1947; 13p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 32)
    - "Aspect Omnibus". Multiple copies of a 15-page proposal for a book series, as well as other publishing ideas, 1947; typescript and carbon copy (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 33)
    - Prose sketches in English, late 1940s; 3.2.19 (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 34-35)
      Short prose pieces (circa 1p. ea.), mostly untitled, numbered 1-62 and several unnumbered pieces. Several pieces are dated Reader's Digest, 1-17-1949. Includes multiple versions of each piece. Typescript and cc. with numerous h. corr.
      - Sketches numbered 1-31, ca. 115p (Box 12 (3.2.19-Prose sketches in English), Folder 34)
      - Sketches numbered 32-62 and unnumbered, ca. 147p (Box 12 (3.2.19-Prose sketches in English), Folder 35)
    - Short prose fragments. False starts, fragmentary pieces, late 1940s; 66p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 36)
    - Prose and poetry submissions to Atlantic Monthly, Reader's Digest, Saturday Evening Post, etc., late 1940s; 39p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 37)
      Some duplication.
    - "Introducing the Index: I Can Read the Alphabet, Can't I?", 1949; 7p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 38)
      Earlier version. Typescript cc. 17p.
    - "Filing Rules for the Arrangement of the 'Index'", 1949 February 22; 6p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 38)
    - "If you were the only one in charge of Indexing the Funk & Wagnall's Encyclopedia", 1949 February 13; 2p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 38)
    - "Cable Addresses. An Unexplored Mine of Psychology", ca. 1949; 10p (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 39)
      Notes and background material. Autograph and Typescript 38p.
    - "Legend Is Stronger Than Fact", Undated (Box 12 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 40)
      Typescript 11p. Cc. 11p. Draft of an earlier version. Typescript with numerous h. corr. 14p.
    - Short prose, drafts of articles, in English, 1950s; 27p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1)
    - Publication attempts, notes, 1951 (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 2)
      Autograph and Typescript 19p. 1 cl.
    - "Fragesagewagetagebuch", 1952 March (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 3)
      Outline and description. Typescript 10p. Text, divided into three sections. Typescript cc. 38p., 43p., 45p.
    - "Spiel und Fügung. Ein Fragesagewagetagebuch". Written in Brooklyn, 1950-1957 (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 4)
      2 copies. Typescript and cc. 11p. ea.
    - "From the Notebook of a Law Student. Written Between Classes and Sometimes During". Winter semester, 1953-1954 (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 5)
    - "From the Notebook of a Law Student. Written Between Classes and Sometimes During", Spring semester 1954 (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 5)
      2 copies. Typescript and cc. 17p. ea.
    - "From the Notebook of a Law Student. Written Between Classes and Sometimes During", Summer session 1954 (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 5)
      2 copies. Typescript and cc. 10 p. ea.
    - "A Lawyer Listens to the Goldberg Variations", 1958 November 03; 3p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 6)
      Also program and program notes.
    - "The Civil Rights Frontier". Draft of an article, Undated (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 7)
      Autograph 13p. Notes. Typescript 4p.
    - "The Road to Innocence", Undated (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 8)
      3 copies. Typescript and cc. 2p. ea. Earlier version. Typescript 1p.
    - "The Tree of Knowledge", 1957 (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 9)
      Notes. Autograph 34p. Typescript 4p. Schematic diagram. Autograph pc. 4p. Printed materials. 3 items.
    - Notes, miscellaneous lists of names, 1950s; ca. 50p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1960s; ca. 20p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 11)
    - "Hitler Died in 1963", Undated (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 12)
      4 copies. Typescript and cc. 3p. ea. Earlier versions. Typescript 2p. Cc. 3p. German version entitled "Hitler starb 1963". Typescript cc. 3p. Earlier version. 2 copies. Typescript and cc. 3p. ea.
    - Theory of aphorisms Notes, ca. 1960s; 13p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 13)
    - "Copyright by Anon", ca. 1960s (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 14)
      2 copies of article written in 1955 for copyright law course taught by Walter J. Derenberg. Cc. 21p. ea. Revised text. Undated, ca. 1965, ca. 17p.
    - "Copyright by Anon". Notes concerning publication (Dec. 1966) in the American Bar Association Journal, 1965-1966; 10p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 15)
      Draft of a L. to Richard Bentley, Editor-in-chief, American Bar Association Journal. Typescript 2p. Materials. 4 items.
    - "Rediscovering Kurt Bauchwitz: Der Lebendige". Article published jointly with Wayne Wonderley in The University of Dayton Review, VI, No. 2 (Fall 1969), pp. 3-26, Undated; 3.2.44 (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 16-18)
      - Article, 62p (Box 13 (3.2.44-"Rediscovering Kurt Bauchwitz: Der Lebendige". Art), Folder 16)
      - Earlier version of essay, 2 copies 26p each (Box 13 (3.2.44-"Rediscovering Kurt Bauchwitz: Der Lebendige". Art), Folder 17)
        Another version dated August 3, 1968 Typescript with numerous h. corr. 29p.
      - Notes, 1968; ca. 80p (Box 13 (3.2.44-"Rediscovering Kurt Bauchwitz: Der Lebendige". Art), Folder 18)
    - "The Why of 'Judge Not!'", 1970 April 6; 4p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 19)
      Another version. Cc. 3p. (published in PHP. A Forum for a Better World, Kyoto, Japan, Oct. 1970, pp. 22-23).
    - "Psychedelics and the Law". Notes, research materials, Undated; ca. 95p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 20)
    - "Psychedelics and the Law. A Prelude in Question Marks", Undated; 21p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 21)
      (published in Psychedelic Review, Cambridge, MA, I, No. 4 (1974), pp. 379-392); earlier drafts of article, dated October 1963. Typescript and cc. with numerous h. corr. 3c. 5p. ea. Another early version. Typescript with h. corr. 7p.
    - "The Addict and the Law.' By Alfred R. Lindemann". Review, Undated; 3p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 22)
      Earlier version. Typescript with numerous h. corr. 4p. Notes. Autograph 6p.
    - "Biotechnics", Undated; 22p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 23)
    - "Outline of a Research Project", Undated; 2p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 23)
    - "Biosophic Seminar", 1948 January 05; 10p (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 23)
    - Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided into categories of classification on topics in biosophy (the art of living), dating from ca. 1948-1950; 3.2.52; typescript - ca. 2400 items (Box 13 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 24-42)
      - Handwritten alphabetical index to categories of classification (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 24)
        Autograph 3p. Notes to divisions of categories. Autograph 8p.
      - B - Note slips on topics: biosophy, biotechnics, biotechnic theory, behavior, bias, 304 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 25)
      - C - Note slips on topics: conscience, character, 7 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 26)
      - D - Notes slips on topics: definitions, death, dreams, 121 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 27)
      - E - Note slips on topics: experience, evolution, experimentation, ethics, education, environment, 185 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 28)
      - F - Note slips on topics: faith and religion, free will, 39 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 29)
      - H - Note slips on topics: happiness, health, habits, humor, 131 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 30)
      - L - Note slips on topics: language, life style, love, 302 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 31)
      - M - Note slips on topics: mental hygiene, methodology, miscellaneous, 75 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 32)
        Also miscellaneous materials pertaining to mental health issues.
      - N - Note slips on topics: neighbor, 24 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 33)
      - O - Note slips on topics: organization (seminar), 56 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 34)
      - P - Note slips on topics: philosophy, polemical, pacifism, politics, psychology, 423 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 35)
      - Q - Note slips on topics: quotations (book titles), 14 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 36)
      - R - Note slips on topics: reality, reason, religion, 160 items (Box 13 (3.2.52-Definitions of terms, words, expressions, divided ), Folder 37)